{"tossups": [{"question": "Following the signing of a petition named for this area, John Bowne illegally housed Quakers in his home. William Steinway of Steinway & Sons built the Steinway Village in this area\u2019s Astoria neighborhood. Thirty people signed the Flushing Remonstrance in this borough against Director-General Peter Stuyvesant. This borough is the sight of the Unisphere, built for the 1964 New York World\u2019s Fair. For ten points, name this New York City Borough, the location of John F. Kennedy International Airport.", "answer": "<em><b> Queens</b></em>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "This man was legendarily scolded by a peasant woman after letting her griddle cakes burn. This leader\u2019s father, Aethelwulf, sent him to Rome to be coronated by Pope Leo IV. He isn\u2019t William the Conqueror, but this king compiled his law code in the \u201cDoom Book.\u201d This leader forced the Danish King, Guthrum, to convert to Christianity after defeating him at the Battle of Eddington. For ten points, name this \u201cGreat\u201d King of Wessex.", "answer": "<em><b> Alfred</b></em> The Great", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "Testimony by this man was used by the Supreme Court in the Betamax Case which dealt with the home video market, leading to approval of PBS funding. This Presbyterian minister also worked in television and offered children relief during the First Gulf War and the Invasion of Iraq. Daniel Tiger, Henrietta Pussycat and King Friday feature on this man\u2019s show. For ten points, name this cardigan-wearing creator of a PBS show titled for his namesake \u201cNeighborhood.\u201d", "answer": "Mr.<em><b> Rogers</b></em> (accept Fred<em><b> Rogers</b></em>)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "Despite losing most of his money in an Algerian oil deal, this man refused to appear in alcohol and cigarette commercials, claiming it would be a bad influence. This man\u2019s autobiography To Hell and Back was adapted into a movie in which he starred. This man slept with a loaded gun under his pillow as indication of his PTSD after single-handedly holding off hundreds of Germans in the Colmar Pocket. For ten points, name this Medal of Honor winner and movie star.", "answer": "Audie<em><b> Murphy</b></em>", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {"question": "In order to downplay a defeat, this country\u2019s Gothic Line was renamed to the Green Line by Albert Kesselring. This country\u2019s forces faced Operation Avenger in which bombers controversially destroyed the historic abbey of Monte Cassino. A dead body with false war plans was floated ashore prior to the invasion of this country in Operation Husky. This country\u2019s capital fell on June 5th, 1944 after an offensive from Anzio. For ten points, Mark Clark controversially captured what country\u2019s capital in 1944?", "answer": "<em><b> Italy</b></em>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "Ismail al-Azhari was the first prime minister of this country, where the Anyanya rebels fought a civil war from 1955 to 1972 that was ended by the Addis Ababa Agreement. The Nuer White Army enlisted child soldiers during this country\u2019s Second Civil War which ended in 2005. The Justice and Equality Movement are fighting the Janjaweed in, for ten points, what African country led by Omar al-Bashir whose Southern neighbor seceded in 2011?", "answer": "Republic of the<em><b> Sudan</b></em> (accept North<em><b> Sudan</b></em>, do not accept \u201cSouth Sudan\u201d)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "During this man\u2019s early career as the Allied head of Combined Operations, he planned both the successful bombing of St. Nazaire and the disastrous Dieppe Raid. This man hired Cyril Radcliffe to form a line of partition to separate the Muslim League and the Indian National Congress following independence. For ten points, identify British India\u2019s last Viceroy who was assassinated by the IRA when a bomb exploded aboard his fishing boat.", "answer": "Louis<em><b> Mountbatten</b></em> (accept 1st Earl<em><b> Mountbatten</b></em> of Burma)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "During a civil war in this country, the HMS Orestes faced fire from both sides and a commander using the alias \u201cCarlos de Ponza\u201d led the navy. Miguel I entered exile after this country\u2019s Liberal Wars. After this country\u2019s King Sebastian died at Alcacer Quibir, this country entered a union with its neighbor until the Restoration War. Like Spain, French forces invaded this country in the Peninsular War. The House of Braganza ruled, for ten points, what Iberian country?", "answer": "<em><b> Portugal</b></em>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "According to Xenophon\u2019s version of this event, the central figure refused the aid of his friends because the possibility of death was better than senility. According to one source of this event, the central figure offered to pay a fine of 30 mina as an alternative to banishment and execution. As a result of this event, a certain philosopher was forced to drink hemlock. For ten points, name this event where the teacher of Plato was convicted of the corruption of the youth of Athens.", "answer": "<em><b> Trial</b></em> of<em><b> Socrates</b></em> (accept<em><b> apology</b></em> of<em><b> Socrates</b></em>, accept equivalents to \u201cTrial,\u201d do NOT accept or prompt on the death of execution of Socrates)", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {"question": "This man headed off Napoleon III\u2019s attempt to annex Hawaii with the statement that his country would not \u201cstand for any such action.\u201d This man unsuccessfully ran for president on the ticket of the Know-Nothing Party in the election of 1856. This man dismissed his predecessor\u2019s cabinet and took the lead in pushing through Henry Clay\u2019s proposals in the Compromise of 1850. For ten points, name the last Whig president of the United States who succeeded Zachary Taylor.", "answer": "Millard<em><b> Fillmore</b></em>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "The League of Augsburg was formed to combat this man who was forced to sign the Treaty of Ryswick after the Nine Years\u2019 War. This man solidified his rule after the Treaties of Rastatt and Utrecht ended The Fronde which was prompted by his attempts to gain control of the Spanish Throne. For ten points name this French monarch who fought the War of the Spanish Succession and was known as the\u201cSun King.\u201d", "answer": "<em><b> Louis XIV</b></em> (accept<em><b> Louis the Great</b></em>, prompt on \u201cSun King\u201d before mentioned)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "Jesse Jackson drew controversy in this election year for using an anti-Semitic slur in New York City during his candidacy for the Democratic nomination. That nomination was eventually won by a man who lampooned a rival by referencing Wendy\u2019s \u201cWhere\u2019s the Beef\u201d ads. The first woman to appear on a major party presidential ticket, Geraldine Ferraro, ran in this year. For ten points, name this election year in which only the District of Columbia and Minnesota voted for Walter Mondale over Ronald Reagan.", "answer": "<em><b> 1984</b></em>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "Irving Langmuir conducted his Nobel-winning research at this company, whose namesake \u201cRealty Plots\u201d were acquired from Union College during the 19th century. In the 1980s, a CEO of this company popularized \u201crank and yank\u201d policies while re-acquiring RCA. This company was one of the original 12 members of the Dow Jones Industrial Average and has been led by Jeff Immelt and Jack Welch. For ten points, name this U.S. conglomerate founded by Thomas Edison.", "answer": "<em><b> General Electric</b></em> Company (accept<em><b> G.E.</b></em>)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "A group of students rallied in support of this event at the Paul Sauve Arena. During this event, one politician stated \u201cgo on and bleed\u201d to \u201cweak-kneed bleeding hearts\u201d before telling Tim Ralfe, \u201cJust watch me.\u201d This event saw the kidnapping of British diplomat James Cross and the execution of Pierre Laporte. The War Measures Act suspended civil liberties during this event by Prime Minister Pierre Trudeau. For ten points, name this 1970 crisis started by the Front de Liberation du Quebec.", "answer": "<em><b> October Crisis</b></em> (accept<em><b> La Crise d\u2019Octobre</b></em>, accept<em><b> FLQ crisis</b></em>)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "This university was originally founded in a town named for the naval hero Peter Warren. The father of the man for whom this university was re-named was involved in smuggling and the slave trade. The creation of this university was supported by the First Baptist Church of America and was proposed in a petition drafted by three inhabitants of Newport. Located in the same state as Roger Williams University, for ten points, name this Ivy League institution originally named the College of Rhode Island.", "answer": "<em><b> Brown</b></em> University (accept College of<em><b> Rhode Island</b></em> and Providence Plantations before\u201cre-named\u201d)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "One side in this battle was forced to retreat after a heavy storm at Wiehen rendered their bows unusable. The losing side in this battle withdrew to the Kalkriese Hills, only to be ambushed by the spy Hermann, also known as Arminius. Reports of this battle allegedly prompted emperor Augustus to shout,\u201cVarus, give me back my legions!\u201d For ten points, name this 9 AD battle in which a Roman army was ambushed in the forests of Germany.", "answer": "Battle of the<em><b> Teutoberg Forest</b></em> (accept<em><b> Varian Disaster</b></em> before \u201cVarus\u201d)", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {}, {"question": "In one song from this musical, a woman asks \u201cShould I bring him down? Should I scream and shout?\u201dIn another song, the protagonist of this musical is asked \u201cWho are you? What have you sacrificed?\u201d by a choir of angels. This musical was banned in South Africa and has been condemned by both Jews and Christians. This musical features the musical number \u201cPilate\u2019s Dream.\u201d For ten points, name this rock musical based on the life of a New Testament figure, composed by Tim Rice and Andrew Lloyd Webber.", "answer": "<em><b> Jesus Christ Superstar</b></em>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Other Fine Arts - Misc Arts"}, {}, {"question": "This man was accused of cowardice after fainting at the Battle of Contreras due to injuries suffered in the fall of his horse. This president supported compromise on sectional issues and sent troops to Boston to recapture escaped slave Anthony Burns. Stephen Douglas persuaded this man to sign an act resolving the legality of slavery in two namesake western territories by popular sovereignty. For ten points, name this Democratic president who signed the Kansas-Nebraska Act.", "answer": "Franklin<em><b> Pierce</b></em>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>The newspaper The Daily Eagle was influential in the construction of this project. After this project\u2019s supervisor fell ill with decompression sickness, his wife Emily took over as chief engineer. In an epic poem dedicated to this structure, (+) Hart Crane described it as\u201cacross the harbor, silver-paced.\u201d This structure\u2019s integrity was tested when P.T. Barnum led 21 elephants across it as well as by Hurricane (*)</b> Sandy in 2012. This structure\u2019s Park Row exit ran right under 1 Police Plaza and was closed after 9/11. For ten points, Chester A. Arthur opened what bridge linking Manhattan to a Long Island borough?", "answer": "<em><b> Brooklyn Bridge</b></em> (accept<em><b> East River Bridge</b></em>)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b>Close to ten percent of the population of this country died during an 1866-1868 period known as the \u201cgreat hunger years.\u201d In 1827, this country\u2019s \u201cMother Church\u201d was burned in the Great Fire of (+) Turku. Fredrik Idestam was an engineer from this country who founded a paper mill company in Tampere that would go on to become Nokia. The sortovuodet was a period of Russification partly inspired by (*) </b> Karelian nationalist movements in this country. For ten points, name this country, the home of notable artists such as Nobel Prize-winning author Frans Eemil Sillanpaa and composer Jean Sibelius.", "answer": "<em><b> Finland</b></em>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b>This man decided to walk an equivalent distance all around the world, ending at Guadalajara, Mexico, when he was released from prison. The Theory of Ruin Value was created by this man who posited that (+) buildings should be designed to produce pleasing ruins. A famous photograph places this man with both his superior and sculptor Arno Breker in front of the (*) </b> Eiffel Tower. William Shirer claimed this architect did not, \u201cshirk his responsibility and his guilt\u201d towards war crimes. For ten points, name this minister of armaments who denied knowledge of the Holocaust and was known as \u201cThe Nazi who said sorry\u201d.", "answer": "Albert<em><b> Speer</b></em>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b>A ship carrying gold to this modern country, the Doddington, was wrecked at Port Elizabeth. A general who fought in this country was called \u201cheaven-born,\u201d and that man selected Warren Hastings to be a resident before facing John (+) Burgoyne\u2019s attacks over reforms. The Siege of Arcot took place in this country. Robert Clive made his fortune in this country where he beat Mir Jafar at the Battle of (*)</b> Plassey. The French took Madras in, for ten points, what country where the United Kingdom controlled regions including Bengal?", "answer": "Republic of<em><b> India</b></em>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "<b>While analyzing clerical and administrative workers, this author coined the term \u201cwhite collar.\u201d This man\u2019s \u201cDead Hand\u201d series includes a work that critiques newspaper moguls like William Randolph Hearst titled (+) The Brass Check. After losing the 1934 California gubernatorial election, this man authored I, Candidate for Governor: And How I Got Licked. Another work by this man led Congress to pass the (*)</b> Pure Food and Drug Act after detailing the horrors of Jurgus Rudkus and the Lithuanian immigrants in Chicago. For ten points, name this muckraker who wrote The Jungle.", "answer": "Upton<em><b> Sinclair</b></em>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b>During this conflict, John Doukas was able to reassert his rule in Chios and Ephesus after the battle of Dorylaeum where the forces of Alp Arslan were decisively defeated. This conflict\u2019s leaders included Bohemond of Taranto and (+) Godfrey of Bouillon, who were called to action after the battle of Manzikert resulted in the Seljuk Turks encroaching on the realms of (*)</b> Alexius I Komnenos, the Byzantine emperor. For ten points, Urban II called for what holy war during the Council of Clermont that ultimately placed Jerusalem in Christian hands?", "answer": "<em><b> First Crusade</b></em> (accept<em><b> Princes\u2019 Crusade</b></em>)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b>After this figure\u2019s father died, this figure asked Abu Bakr to relinquish the Sadak Oasis and refused to speak to him when he refused. This figure\u2019s (+) dowry was paid by a man who sold his shield but then had the shield returned as a wedding gift. Along with her husband, this woman is the common ancestor of all people claiming the title of \u201csayyid.\u201dThis woman was the only surviving child of (*)</b> Khadijah bint Khuwaylid. In Twelver Shia Islam, this figure is the only infallible woman. For ten points, name this wife of Ali and daughter of Muhammad.", "answer": "<em><b> Fatimah</b></em> bint Muhammad (accept<em><b> Fatimah</b></em> al-Zahra)", "metadata": "Religion - Religion"}, {"question": "<b>This man acquired a reputation for cruelty after flogging one of his merchant seaman and was forced to change his name to evade arrest after killing a mutinous crewman in a pay dispute. During raiding operations in the North and Irish Seas, this man\u2019s sloop, the USS (+) Ranger, captured the HMS Drake after a single ship duel. In the Battle of Flambough Head, this man\u2019s ship fought the British HMS (*) </b> Serapis to a standstill, forcing its surrender. For ten points, name this legendary Revolutionary War commander of the Bon Homme Richard who reputedly said, \u201cI have not yet begun to fight.\u201d", "answer": "John Paul<em><b> Jones</b></em>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b>Forces from this city\u2019s empire were victorious at the Battle of Carchemish, which ended Egyptian incursions into Asia. At two separate intervals, separated by a millennium, this city may have had the highest (+) population in the world. In 323 BC, this city was the site of the death of Alexander the Great under mysterious circumstances. Under (*) </b> Nebuchadnezzar II, this city expanded its influence through Mesopotamia. For ten points, name this city where Hammurabi issued a code of laws and its namesake Hanging Gardens were built.", "answer": "<em><b> Babylon</b></em>", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {}], "bonuses": []}